翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
The last thing I want to talk about today, and something that will be really important for project zero,
今天我想谈的最后一件事，对项目0非常重要
and indeed your entire future programming career,
甚至有关于你未来的整个编程生涯
is using libraries.
就是使用库
So one of the most amazing things about computer science is that
计算机科学最惊奇的事情之一
any piece of code I write can be instantly sent to you
就是我写的任何代码都可以立即发送给你
and reused and doesn't matter how complicated it is.
并且可以复用，不管代码有多复杂
I can write a function that, for example, takes the human genome and simulates what the person's face looks like.
例如我可以写一个函数，通过人类基因组模拟长相
In theory, that might be possible.
这在理论上是可行的
And once I wrote it, I could just send that to you as a library.
写好后就可以将它封装成库发送给你
And you could just use it as a function in whatever you wanted to use it for.
你可以随心所欲地把它当作一个函数来使用
And that's something that is really one of the most amazing and cool things about being a programmer, right.
这对程序员来说真是一件很酷的事情
Anything anybody builds, it's yours.
任何人创造的东西都可以为你所用
So you should learn how to take advantage of all the libraries people out there have written.
所以你应该学会如何使用其他人写的库
So there are tons of things out there that people have written.
外界各种各样的库太多了
And in this class we're going to give you everything you need.
我会告诉你在这门课上所需的所有库
We're not going to ask you to go find the appropriate library on the internet and use it.
无需自己在网上搜索合适的库使用
And in fact, we're going to ask that you don't.
这样做没必要
So the libraries that we're going to use include all those things like the built-in libraries.
我们要用到这些库，比如内置库 Math
So the math class can compute square roots and the integer class you convert strings to integers, and so forth.
Math 类可以计算平方根，Integer 类可以将字符串转换为整数，以此类推
And we're also going to use another big library known as the Princeton Standard Library I'll describe in a moment.
我们还将使用一个大型库——普林斯顿标准库，稍后会介绍
Now we may add additional libraries for the later projects, but we'll have at least these.
以后的项目可能还有其他库，但这些是基本
So as a programmer, you really want to use what's out there, because it'll first save you the trouble of writing code.
作为一名程序员，你可以使用现有的功能简化开发
But secondly, that it avoids you introducing any kind of weird bugs.
还可以避免任何奇怪的错误
So there's all kinds of stories of people trying to write their own cryptographic libraries.
比如因为各种原因，人们试图编写自己的加密库
Because they think, OK, well, you know, I'm writing this program, so really I ought to be the one writing the key exchange code or whatever it may be.
他们编写程序，希望交换密钥之类的
And you get some tiny little detail,
一些微小的细节
some subtle little detail, and it really compromises your security.
可能真的会危及你的程序安全
So if you use libraries that have already been tested and used by tons of people out there in the world,
如果你使用的库已经被世界上成千上万的人测试和使用
chances are it's going to be less buggy.
很可能它就没有这些问题
I mean, it might not be.
也可能仍然有问题
There have been major bugs in widely used pieces of software.
一些广泛使用的软件也存在重大错误
But chances are, you will do a worse job.
但很可能你做得更差
Now the downside is you're going to spend some time learning how each of these libraries works.
缺点是你要花点时间来了解这些库是如何工作的
So it's sort of like the equivalent of when you first start programming it's so tempting to write everything yourself.
这就相当于你第一次编程时，很想自己写出所有东西
And I kind of liken it to imagine you have a giant chunk of wood and you want to cut it in half.
假设你有一大块木头，想把它切成两半
And you have a saw.
你有一把锯子
So you could, I mean, you know how a saw works.
你得知道锯子是如何工作的
You go like this and it gets chopped in half.
你这样做，木头就会被切成两半
And even if it takes you two hours or two days,
即使你要花两个小时或两天的时间
you know you can get there.
但早晚可以做到
Now the better way to chop giant pieces of wood is probably to use a big machine like some kind of giant say table saw or whatever.
现在使用机器来锯木头可能更好，比如台锯之类的巨型机器
But that means you have to learn how the tool works.
你必须学习这个工具是如何工作的
And sometimes that can be really annoying.
这有时候很烦人
Now what I would advise you to do is avoid the temptation to hacksaw everything and to think smart wherever you can.
不使用锯子锯所有东西，尽可能仔细思考
And often that process involves using a library.
这个过程通常涉及到使用库
So if you want to use a library, you have know that the library exists,
如果你想使用库，就必须知道库的存在
and you have to know how it works.
必须知道它是如何工作的
So how to use one you find one?
那么如何找到你想使用的呢？
Well, one way is to find a tutorial.
一种方法是找个教程
You'll find on the web or on YouTube people have videos for commonly used libraries.
网络或者 YouTube 上会有常用库的使用视频
Like let's say the Django library if we're doing web programming, right.
比如说 Django 库，如果我从事网络编程
So out there there's I bet you dozens of videos on YouTube that explain how it works, and that's great.
我跟你打赌 YouTube 上有几十个视频解释了它是如何工作的
Now sometimes you just want to look at the documentation
有时看看文档就够了
and see how it works in a way that the designers of the library thought was most important.
知道它是如何以库的设计者认为最重要的方式工作
And one of the things that's really nice about Java is that the library documentation is often quite good.
Java 真正的优点是它的库文档很棒
So we had here converting string to integer in Java.
这里描述了 Java 将字符串转换为整数的方法
But we can actually look up the official documentation for the integer class.
实际上可以查找 Integer 类的官方文档
It's actually usually pretty easy to find.
通常很容易找到
If I just do Java integer in this case it takes me straight to this page.
搜索“Java Integer”，会将我直接带到这个页面
And so what I have here is if we look in this file it lists everything you might want to know about the integer class.
在这个文件中，列出了你可能想知道的所有关于 Integer 类的信息
It's all of the interfaces, all the methods that you might call.
所有的接口，所有的方法
And so if we look at this parseint method,
看一下 parseInt 方法
we can see that it tells us what it does.
我们可以看到，它告诉我们它是做什么的
Parses the string argument as assigned to decimal integer.
解析字符串参数为十进制整数
So it tells you everything you want to know and maybe some extra stuff that you don't really care about or quite understand.
它会告诉你想知道的一切，也许还有一些不太关心的额外信息
Now one thing that's fun about this documentation is even just with what we know so far,
这个文档有趣的一点是，就我们目前所知道的
just a couple of days videos, you can already read this.
短短几天的视频，你已经可以阅读这个了
I mean, it says it's a public method.
上面说这是 public 方法
And we know the public seems to be associated with method somehow.
我们知道 public 与方法有关联
Static, well, it's a static method.
static，这是一个静态方法
So you're using integer dot not like a specific integer.
所以你要使用 Integer. 而不是一个具体的 integer
It returns an int.
它返回一个 int
It's called parseint and it takes a string argument.
它被称为 parseInt，接受一个字符串参数
And you know, we don't know what that means quite yet.
我们还不知道这个的意思
So what I'm going to say here or what I'm saying here is just that the documentation is often quite good,
所以我要说的是，文档通常很棒
and I encourage you to check it out.
我鼓励你们多看看
Because sometimes the concise answer in the library is better than trying to dig through a bunch of tutorials on the web.
因为有时候库中简洁的回答比网上挖空心思搜来的教程好
And then lastly, looking at example code snippets that use a particular library is a great technique.
最后，使用库中示例代码也是一项很好的技能
And that, for example, is why I love Stack Overflow.
例如我喜欢 Stack Overflow 的原因
Because here look, a code snippet.
代码段随处可见
So whenever you use those, I do remind you to cite your sources just in line with good practices.
我要提醒，在使用时最好保留你引用的资源链接
As any kind of creative person, you should always be citing your sources.
作为一个有创造力的人，你应该经常记录你的引用来源
And later we'll talk a little bit more about the official rules for citing things in this course.
稍后我们会讨论这门课中引用的官方规则
So in 61B, again, we're giving you all the libraries you need.
总之在 61B 中，我们会提供你所需的所有库
You don't need to get any new ones.
你不需要找新的
And in fact, we ask you not to, because it will make the grader get confused.
事实上要求你不要那样做，因为这会让评分器困惑
So for example, if we have not given you the Apache Commons library, don't use that.
比如我们没有提供 Apache Commons 库，就不要使用它
This right here is just a picture of what the integer documentation looks like.
这是 Integer 文档的一张截图
But you know, this is a video, so who cares,
这是一段视频，不用在乎它
but if you're a slide reader.
但如果阅读幻灯片会有用吧
And then lastly, I want to let you know a little bit more about the Princeton Standard Library.
最后多介绍一下普林斯顿标准库
So I used to teach at Princeton, and one of my colleagues, Kevin Wayne, built this beautiful library
我以前在普林斯顿大学教书，一个同事 Kevin Wayne 构建了这个漂亮的库
for Java that does all kinds of awesome stuff like getting input from the user, reading from profiles,
它可以实现 Java 中很多事情，比如获取用户输入、读取配置文件
drawing, sound.
绘画、声音等
And all of it is a really nice interface.
而且它们的接口很好
So we're going to make heavy use of it,
所以我们会大量使用它
especially in the early parts of the course.
特别是在课程的早期阶段
Later on we'll kind of wean ourselves off of it,
以后会脱离它的
because it's a nonstandard library.
因为这是一个非标准库
But early on, you'll find it's really useful.
但在早期，你会发现它真的很有用
And especially for project zero if you're going to use these heavily because we'll be drawing,
特别是在项目0中大量使用，因为我们需要绘制
you know, planets and all kinds of fun stuff.
行星，以及各种有趣的东西
So the next move for you is to go check out project zero, get started.
下一步就是去看看项目0，赶快开始吧
And get cracking and really start cementing all the knowledge we have from the video so far.
马上动手，巩固目前为止我们在视频中学到的所有知识
And I encourage you to, before you move on to the next videos,
在进入下一个视频之前
really try and make some major headway on project zero.
我鼓励你们在项目0中多多尝试
Because that's where you're going to learn quite a lot is actually trying to build things.
因为在那里你会学到很多，构建一些真实的东西
So that's it for today, and I'll see you next time.
今天就到这里，下次见
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）